Guide to the Fales Library and Special Collections Audio/Video Collection 1960-2011 MSS.306
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fales Library and Special Collections Audio/Video Collection
1960-2011
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fales Library
MSS.306
3 Linear Feet
Arrangement
The collection is organized into four series by format and arranged alphabetically by title. The dates used are the items' copyright years.
Conditions Governing Access
Series I, II, and III are to researchers. Series IV: Film, is closed. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Scope and Content
This collection contains primarily commerically released audio and video materials relating to the Fales Library and Special Collections.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
- Series I: Audio
  Scope and Content
  This series contains audio materials on audiocassette and CD including audiobooks, readings and interviews.
  - Bay Mir Bistu Sheyn: Great Songs of the Yiddish Stage, Volume 2, 2005; cuid21504 (Box 1)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Format: CD
    Duration: 01:08:45
    General
    Vienna Chamber Orchestra
    Sholom Secunda, songwriter
    Alexander Olshanetsky, songwriter
    Elli Jaffe, conductor
  - Ben Kinmont, "I need you," Audio from VHS, MP3 loop, 1992; cuid21606 (Box 7)
    Format: CD-R, Duration: 4 hrs. 38 min.
  - Black House, 2001; cuid21505 (Box 1)
    Format: Audiocassette
    Duration: [26:00:00]
    Stephen King, author
    Peter Straub, author
    Frank Muller, narrator
  - Blues and Haikus, undated; cuid21506 (Box 6)
    Format: Sound Disc: Analog, 33 1/3 rpm; 12 in.
    Duration: unknown
    Jack Kerouac, author
    Al Cohn, artist
    Zoot Sims, artist
  - Cruisin w/ Moxie, 2003; cuid21507 (Box 1)
    Eve Packer, artist
    Noah Howard, songwriter and artist
    Bobby Few, artist
  - Dreamcatcher, 2001; cuid21508 (Box 1)
    Duration: [23:00:00]
    Jeffrey DeMunn, narrator
  - "El Muchacho", 2008; cuid21608 (Box 7)
    Scope and Contents
    Commercially produced CD.
  - Eleanor Roosevelt in Conversation with Ben Grauer, 1957; cuid21509 (Box 6)
  - Fale[s] Bobst Library NUY [NYU], tape 1, 10-20-98; cuid21510 (Box 1)
  - Fale[s] Bobst Library, tape 2, 10-20-98; cuid21511 (Box 1)
  - Fales Library: Adrienne Rich/Atlas of the Known World, 4/29/91; cuid21512 (Box 1)
  - Family Affairs, 1995; cuid21513 (Box 1)
  - Future of the Present: 1998-1999 Season, The, 2001; cuid21514 (Box 1)
    Franlin Furnace Archive, Inc., creator
  - Get Back in the Gutter!, 2010; cuid21515 (Box 1)
    Zero Content, artist Fly, artist CRG, artist and songmastering
  - Hortense Calisher interview with Kay Bonetti, American Audio Prose Library, undated; cuid21516 (Box 1)
    Duration: 00:58:05
  - Hortense Calisher reads excerpts from "Herself" and "Mysteries of Motion," American Audio Prose Library, undated; cuid21517 (Box 1)
    Duration: 00:49:48
  - If You Could See Me Now, 1986; cuid21518 (Box 1)
    Duration: [02:30:00]
    Keir Dullea, narrator
  - In with the Out Crowd, 1998; cuid21519 (Box 1)
    Duration: [01:05:00]
    Bob Holman, artist
  - Interview with Reynolds Price, American Audio Prose Library, 1982; cuid21520 (Box 1)
    Duration: 01:00:00
    Lyn Ballard, interviewer
  - Interview with Toni Morrison, American Audio Prose Library, 1983; cuid21521 (Box 1)
    Duration: 01:18:00
    Kay Bonetti, interviewer
  - John Watts, 5/18/03; cuid21522 (Box 1)
  - Lady Chatterley's Lover, 1959; cuid21523 (Box 6)
    Pamela Brown, narrator
    Howard Sackler, director
  - LeRoi Jones at Panther Benefit, Fillmore East, 1968-06; 2018; cuid6287 (Box 2, Reel cuid6287, E-records fales_MSS306, E-records MSS30.cuid6287)
    Amiri Baraka (LeRoi Jones) gives a 15-minute address to an audience of Black Panther supporters, an event held at the Fillmore East in New York City, 1968.
    Original format: 1/4" Open Reel Audio, Duration: 18 min.
    Baraka, Amiri, 1934-2014
  - Merry Fortune, 1981; cuid21524 (Box 6)
    Format: Sound Disc: Analog, 45 rpm; 12 in.
    Duration: [00:21:00]
  - Mother Number 9, 1968; cuid21525 (Box 6)
  - [Mrs. Corso at Keroac's Home], 1963-07; 2018; cuid6286 (Box 5, Reel cuid6286, E-records fales_MSS306, E-records cuid6286)
    Track 1: Men discuss the cultural concerns of their day. Beat Generation figures are mentioned (Jack Kerouac, Neal Cassady and Allen Ginsberg).
    Track 2: Radio broadcasts of news and music (jazz, pop and classical).
    Original format: 1/4" Open Reel Audio, Duration: 136 min.
  - "Music from Living on the Earth," Alicia Bay Laurel, 2000; cuid21607 (Box 7)
  - No Deposit No Return, undated; cuid21526 (Box 6)
    Format: Sound Disc: Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.
  - On Freedom's Side: The Songs and Poems of Aaron Kramer, 1974; cuid21527 (Box 6)
    Viki Ann Diamond, artist
    Karl Finger, artist
    Joan Fishman, artist
  - P.O.W., Recorded Live in Amsterdam, 2/23/91; cuid21528 (Box 1)
    Lydia Lunch, artist
  - Panjandrum, undated; cuid21529 (Box 6)
    artists/poets: Patrick Todd, Major Ursa, Alan Ginsberg, Nanos Valaoritis, John Harriss, Dennis Koran, David Gitin, Robert Bly, Anthony Shonwald, George Hitchcock, Don Cushman, George Ushanoff, John Logan.
  - Poetry for the Beat Generation, cuid21530 (Box 6)
    Duration: [00:39:00]
    Steve Allen, narrator
  - Reynolds Price reading "A Long and Happy Life," "The Names and Faces if Heroes," "Permanent Errors," "The Surface of the Earth," "The Source of Light" (excerpts), American Audio Prose Library, 1982; cuid21531 (Box 1)
    Duration: 01:20:00
  - Songs for Summer, 2002; cuid21532 (Box 2)
    Duration: 01:1:28
    Mark Kostabi, artist
  - Songs to Texts by James Joyce, undated; cuid21533 (Box 6)
    Patricia Neway, artist
    Robert Colston, artist
  - Talisman, The, 2001; cuid21534 (Box 2)
    Format: Aduiocassette
    Duration: [28:00:00]
  - Tape Poems, 1969; cuid21535 (Box 2)
    Format: 1/4" Audio Reel
    Duration: 00:54:00
    Eduardo Costa, editor
    John Perreault, editor
  - [Taylor Mead: Pink Peny, NYC, Ludlow St], 2003-06-27; cuid21604 (Box 7)
    Format: Audio cassette, Duration: 90 min.
  - Toni Morrison reading "Tar Baby" (excerpts), American Audio Prose Library, 1983; cuid21536 (Box 2)
    Duration: 00:55:00
  - window:9/11, 2002; cuid21537 (Box 2)
    Duration: 00:09:23
    Eve Packer, songwriter and artist
    Noah Howard, artist
  - Zero Content: Greatest Kckn Hits, [2001]; cuid21538 (Box 2)
    Roger Manning, songwriter
    fckn Partridge Family, songwriter
  - Zone Benefit, 1982-01-25; cuid21605; 2 Cassettes two parts (Box 7)
    Format: Audio cassette, Duration: 120 min. (60 min. x 2)
    Housing annotation includes the following names: Jon Gibson, Brad Webster, Spalding Gray, Jonas Mekas, and Mabou Mines.
  - Landing Signals, An Anthology of Sacramento Poets, 1985 (Box 7)
    A paperback book with two accompanying audiocassettes, recordings of poets reading their work. The book is edited by Douglas Blazek, Ann Menebroker, and C.K. Dobbs.
  - A Certain Level of Denial by Karen Finely, 1994 (Box 7)
    Format: Audio CD
  - LT's Theory of Pets by Stephen King, a Live Reading by the Author, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Digitas, New York Digital Review of Arts & Literature (Box 7)
    An interactive CD-ROM of art and literature, featuring the work of John Farris, Elizabeth Murray, Paul Beatty, Andres Serrano, David Hammons, Shalom, Hal Sirowitz, Joseph Overstreet, Darius James, and Bob Holman.
    Format: CD-ROM
- Series II: Video
  This series contains moving image material on videotape and dvd including music and art performances.
  - Anthony Bourdain Parts Unknown: 611 lower East Side-EXT, 2018; cuid21589; 2 dvd-r disks duplicates (Box 7)
    Format: DVD-R
  - Anti-Credo, 1988; cuid21539 (Box 2)
    Format: VHS Duration: 00:30:00
    Monty Cantsin, artist
  - Big Thumbs, 1986; cuid21540 (Box 2)
    Format: VHS Duration: 01:20:00
    Jamie Gillia, actor
    David Lipman, actor
    Janette Sinclair, actress
  - Cincinnati's Imperfect Moment: The Robert Mapplethorpe Exhibit Controversy, 1998; cuid21541 (Box 2)
    Format: VHS Duration: 01:27:00
    Kelly A. Gorth, creator
  - Cinema of Transgression, [1992]; cuid21542 (Box 2)
    Format: VHS
    Duration: 02:27:00
    filmmakers: Richard Kern, Tessa Hughes-Freeland, Holly Adams, David Wojnarowicz Nick Zedd, Jeri Cain Rossi, Tommy Turner, Beth B, Henry Jones, Kenbra Pfahler, Jon Moritsugu.
  - Concrete TV: Never Hard Enough, 2008; cuid21543 (Box 2)
    Ron A. Rocheleau, filmmaker
    Format: DVD
    Duration: [09:00:00]
  - Confessions of a Porn Star, 1995; cuid21544 (Box 3)
    Eric Bogosian, performer
    Barbara Dare, performer
  - David Wojnarowicz, Programs 1 and 2, London Lesbian and Gay Film Festival at the National Film Theatre, April 2002; cuid21545 (Box 3)
    Duration: 01:04:00
  - Downtown New York, 1986; cuid21546 (Box 3)
    Duration: 00:58:00
    Willoughby Sharp, creator
  - Drag Show Video Vérité V, Joe E. Jeffreys, 2011; cuid21601 (Box 7)
    Format: DVD-R, Duration: 58 min.
  - Drawing the Line: A Portrait of Keith Haring, 1989; cuid21547 (Box 3)
    Duration: 00:30:00
    Elisabeth Aubert, director
    Gina Belafonte, narrator
  - Erich Maria Remarque: a Biography in Pictures, undated; cuid21548 (Box 3)
    Duration: 00:15:40
  - Funky Pu[n]ky Chic, undated; cuid21549 (Box 3)
  - "Gooseflesh", Charles Ludlam, undated; cuid21596; 2 videodisc (dvd) two parts (Box 7)
  - Hardly Gold, 1997; cuid21550 (Box 3)
    William Wegman, filmmaker
    Hardly Boys, performers
  - Judson and Fragments, undated; cuid21551 (Box 3)
    Duration: 00:15:16
  - Kool Logic Sessions: Poems, Pop Songs, Laugh Tracts, 2005; cuid21552 (Box 3)
    Duration: 01:21:00
    Urayoan Noel, artist
    Monxo Lopez, composer
  - Laments, 1989; cuid21553 (Box 3)
    Jenny Holzer, artist
    Contains one VHS and one (unpaged) booklet.
  - Last Address, 2009; cuid21554 (Box 3)
    Ira Sachs, filmmaker
  - Last Address, [2010]; cuid21555 (Box 3)
    Duration: 00:09:00
    Ira Sachs, filmmaker and director
  - Laurie Simmons, undated; cuid21556 (Box 3)
  - Miguel Pinero Reading, 1984; cuid21557 (Box 3)
    Duration: 00:20:00
    Jim C., filmmaker
  - Nam June Paik: #1 Video Artist, 3-29-06; cuid21558 (Box 3)
    Skip Blumberg, creator
  - NME Story; Once Upon A Time in NY, undated; cuid21602 (Box 7)
  - NOT Performance Art, parts 1 & 2, 1995; cuid21559 (Box 4)
    Tom Zafian, filmmaker
  - NYU Celebration: Amitin Archival Inauguration, 11/21/02; cuid21560 (Box 4)
  - "On the Road with Bob Holman": Episodes 1-3., 2012-02-01-2012-02-15; cuid21594 (Box 7)
    Format: DVD, Duration: 90 min. (30 min. x 3)
    Commercially produced distribution copy of a Rattapallax/Bowery Arts + Science production.
  - Optic Nerve: David Wojnarowicz on CD-ROM, 1999; cuid21592 (Box 7)
  - Peops Show, The vol. 1, 2006; cuid21561 (Box 4)
    Fly, artist
  - Pier Groups - 1999 re-release, cuid21562 (Box 5)
    Adult Male Video.
    Cream of the Crop Entertainment presents "Archer Brown's classic film of love lust under the waves and piers of New York's fabled waterfront."
    A "Cream of the Crop" classic.
    Kieth Anthoni, performer
    Johnny Kovaks, performer
  - Poetry Thin Air Interviews: Chavisa Woods, undated; cuid21563 (Box 4)
    Mitch Corber, videographer and director
    George Spencer, interviewer
  - Poetry Thin Air Interviews: Eve Packer, undated; cuid21564 (Box 4)
  - Poetry Thin Air Interviews: Jeff Wright, undated; cuid21565 (Box 4)
    Mitcher Corber, videographer and director
  - Poetry Thin Air Interviews: Karin Randolph, undated; cuid21566 (Box 4)
  - Poetry Thin Air Interviews: Larissa Shmailo, undated; cuid21567 (Box 4)
  - Poetry Thin Air Interviews: Mitch Corber, undated; cuid21568 (Box 4)
    Susan L. Young, videographer
  - Poetry Thin Air Interviews: Ron Kolm, undated; cuid21569 (Box 4)
  - Poetry Thin Air Interviews: Steve Cannon, undated; cuid21570 (Box 4)
  - Poetry Thin Air Interviews: Steve Dalachinsky, undated; cuid21571 (Box 4)
  - Poetry Thin Air Interviews: Susan Scutti, undated; cuid21572 (Box 4)
  - Polymath, or, The Life and Opinions of Samuel R. Delany, Gentleman, The, 2009; cuid21573 (Box 4)
    Fed Barney Taylor, filmmaker
  - Portrait of Dale Goodson, A: NOT Performance Art, part 3, 1997; cuid21574 (Box 4)
    Duration: 00:45:00
  - Problems of Work: Scientology Applied to the Workaday World, 2010; cuid21575 (Box 4)
    Duration: 01:06:00
    L. Ron Hubbard, author
  - Putt-Modernism - Television Coverage of Exhibition (Artists Space), 1992; cuid21576 (Box 5)
    Duration: [00:30:00]
    Content:
    1. "What's Up in New York?" - Show #106
    2. CBS This Morning - 30 July, 1992
    3. HBO - Night After Night - 14 August, 1992
    4. Fox "Style News" (WNYN) - 10 August, 1992
    5. Channel 2 News (WCBS) - 6 August, 1992
    6. ABC News - World News Now - 13 August, 1992
  - Rapporti Orali e Trasversalita Sonore, 1999; cuid21577 (Box 4)
    Duration: [00:43:00]
    Nicola Frangione, creator
  - Rattapallax Issue 17: Literary Films on DVD, undated; cuid21603 (Box 7)
    Commercially produced distribution copy.
  - Recettes de Mina - Terezin 1944, Les, 2007; cuid21578 (Box 4)
    Duration: 00:47:00
    Anne Georget, filmmaker
  - Red Souvenir, No Sell Out, Promised Land, Lynch: Who Killed, M.J. Stewart?, undated; cuid21579 (Box 4)
    Frank Goldberg, videomaker
  - Richard Minsky, "American Decorated Publishers' Bindings, 1872-1929," Volume 2 CD-ROM, 2009; cuid21609 (Box 7)
  - "Roy Cohn," Brown University, 1993-03-20; cuid21590 (Box 7)
    Housing annotations: Performed by Ron Vawter, Written by Gary Indiana
  - Sex, Drugs, Rock and Roll, 1991; cuid21580 (Box 4)
    Duration: 01:36:00
  - Smalltown Boys, 05/2003; cuid21581 (Box 5)
    Duration: 00:21:00
    Matt Wolf, director
  - Split: Portrait of a Drag Queen, 1992; cuid21582 (Box 5)
    Ellen Fisher Turk, filmmaker
    Andrew Weeks, filmmaker
    International Chrysis, performer
    This file also contains documents and photographs related to this video.
  - Tester, [2005]; cuid21583 (Box 5)
    Duration: 06:00:00
  - TG24, 12/4/02 - 12/7/02; cuid21584 (Box 5)
    Throbbing Gristle, artist
  - "The Bacchae," Charles Ludlam, undated; cuid21597 (Box 7)
  - "Topless Cellist" Charlotte Moorman, 1995; cuid21585 (Box 5)
    Howard Weinberg, filmmaker
    Nam June Paik, filmmaker
  - The History of the Future, 1998; cuid21593 (Box 7)
    A distribution copy of a Franklin Furnace production.
  - U2 Video "One", undated; cuid21586 (Box 5)
  - UNESCO World Day for Audiovisual Heritage, Gay Cable Network Archives, undated; cuid21599 (Box 7)
    A compilation of clips from the Gay Cable Network Archives, screened at UNESCO's World Day for Audiovisual Heritage.
    Format: Digital Betacam, Duration: 12 min.
  - Video Data Bank, Art Institute of Chicago: "Alice Aycock: An Interview." Kate Horsfield and Lyn Blumenthal., 1977; cuid21591 (Box 7)
    Format: VHS, Duration: 37 min. 30 sec.
  - Way it is, The, undated; cuid21587 (Box 5)
    Eric Mitchell, writer and director
- Series III: Data Storage
  - [Dennis Cooper's old blog], 2005-2006; cuid21595 (Box 7)
    Web pages from Dennis Cooper's blog saved as PDF files.
    Format: CD-R
  - [D. Wojnarowicz/J.Vega correspondence], 1970-1990; cuid21598 (Box 7)
    Photo documentation of written correspondence between David Wojnarowicz and Janine Vega.